Morning.
(麻衣)おはよう｡
(咲太)おはようございます｡
Good morning.
眠れなかったの？
一睡もできませんでした｡
You couldn't sleep?
Not a wink.
Are you implying that it's my fault?
私のせいだって言いたいの？
麻衣さんは神経図太すぎ｡
よく熟睡できましたね｡
You've got nerves of steel.
I can't believe you slept like a log.
子どもの頃から 撮影で
あちこちに行ってたから｡
Well, I've traveled for shoots since I was a child.
それに 咲太が隣に寝てるくらい
なんともないの｡
Also, I think nothing of having you sleeping next to me.
いいことを聞いたので
次の機会には
That's good to hear.
I think I'll play some pranks next time.
いろいろと いたずらしようと
思います｡
As if you have the nerve.
そんな度胸なんてないくせに｡
藤沢まで戻って
お昼から学校へ行くんでしょ？
We're going back to Fujisawa and heading to school for the afternoon, right?
準備するから
ちょっと外に出てなさい｡
Step outside for a bit and let me get ready.
《一夜明けても
やっぱり麻衣さんは
It's the next day now,
but it looks like I'm still the only one
who can see Mai-san.
僕以外の誰の目にも
見えていないようだ》
Episode 3: A World without You Alone
I asked yesterday, and they said it'd be fine.
昨日聞いたらさ
全然大丈夫だって言うんだよ｡
いつもどおりだよな｡
It's all the same as usual, right?
麻衣さんのことが
目に入ってないのか
Are they simply not taking notice of you,
or can they really not see you?
本当に見えてないのか｡
I'll go check my class.
教室見てくる｡
(理央)梓川｡
Azusagawa.
悪い知らせだよ｡
Bad news.
Everyone else may have forgotten about Sakurajima-senpai.
私たち以外 桜島先輩のことを
忘れているかもしれない｡
少なくとも
国見は覚えていなかった｡
Kunimi didn't remember her, at least.
Seriously?
ﾎﾝﾄか？
(朋絵)へぇ そうなんだ｡
Oh, really?
It's you.
昨日の…｡
あ…｡
Oh...
You remember Sakurajima-senpai, right?
なぁ 桜島先輩 知ってるよな？
え？ 桜…？
Huh? Sakura what?
Sakurajima Mai, in third year.
３年の桜島麻衣先輩だ｡
(玲奈)ちょっと 朋絵…｡
Hey, Tomoe...
Why's the hospitalization
incident guy talking to you?
(日南子)病院送りの先輩が
なんで？
Don't ask me.
え… わかんないよ｡
And who's this Sakurawhatever-senpai?
(亜矢)ｻｸﾗなんとか先輩って？
行こう｡
Let's go.
How the hell could you forget?
なんで 忘れてんだ
芸能人の桜島先輩だぞ！
I'm talking about Sakurajima-senpai, the actress!
おい おい！
Wait...
Hey!
１つだけ心当たりがある｡
There's one likely reason I can think of.
Get any sleep last night?
昨日の夜は寝たか？
一睡もしてない｡
Not a wink.
私も一睡もしてない｡
Me neither.
(理央)ただの
結果でしかないけど
I know hindsight is twenty-twenty and all,
but that may be why we remember her.
理由は そこにあると思う｡
そこって 寝てないことにか？
Because we haven't slept, you mean?
前にした 観測理論の話は
覚えてる？
Do you remember what I said
about the observation theory before?
ｼｭﾚﾃﾞｨﾝｶﾞｰの猫｡
Schrödinger's cat.
I've always found it absurd,
正直 ﾊﾞｶげてるとは思ってたけど
こうして目の当たりにすると
寒気が走るよ｡
but seeing it in action like this
sends chills down my spine.
思春期症候群に？
違う｡
What, Puberty Syndrome?
No.
(理央)思春期症候群なんてものが
起きる前から
The fact that she was treated like she was invisible in school even before all of this.
あの人が学校の中で
空気のように扱われていたことに｡
私自身も 空気を読んで
Even I went with the flow,
and despite how abnormal it was that
everyone was subconsciously ignoring her,
みんなが桜島先輩を
無自覚に無視してる
異常な状況を
疑問も抱かず 受け入れていた｡
I internalized it without
stopping to think about it.
If anything, one could only do this
if they didn't stop to think about it.
逆に 疑問に思わないから
できるんだろ｡
でも だからこそ 糸口は
But that's exactly why I feel like the key to resolving this is within our school.
この学校の
空気にあるように思える｡
桜島先輩は 学校の誰からも
観測されておらず
Sakurajima-senpai isn't being observed by anyone at school,
destabilizing her state of existence.
存在が確定していない｡
桜島先輩にとって
この学校こそが
To her, this entire school is Schrödinger's box.
猫を入れた箱なんだよ｡
認識と観測が
ｷｰになっているのであれば
If observation and cognizance are playing a key role,
人の意識が働かない睡眠が
then sleep, a state of unconsciousness, can indeed make one forget about her.
記憶をなくす
きっかけになっているという
考え方は 私なりに納得はできる｡
That makes a lot of sense to me.
それって つまり…｡
Wait, you mean...
If I'd fallen asleep last night,
I would've forgotten about her too?
昨日の夜 もし眠っていたら
僕も今頃…｡
Something the matter?
どうかした？
いえ…｡
No.
Don't you have work today?
今日はﾊﾞｲﾄなんでしょ？
でも…｡
But...
Don't ignore your responsibilities.
そういうのは きちんとしなさい
私なら平気だから｡
No need to worry about me.
それじゃ また明日ね｡
See you tomorrow, then.
《誰も麻衣さんを見ていない｡
Nobody sees Mai-san.
麻衣さんは 誰にも
観測されていなくて
She's not being observed by anyone,
which is destabilizing her state of existence.
存在が定まっていなくて
だから 消えてゆく｡
That's why she's disappearing.
誰にも認識してもらえなければ
If no one recognizes you,
you may as well not exist at all.
この世に存在してないのと
同じだから…》
でも 学校が
発端だっていうなら
But if our school really is the cause,
なんで 学校と接点のない人まで
then why are complete outsiders becoming unable to see her?
麻衣さんのことが
見えなくなったりするんだよ｡
桜島先輩が 学校内の空気を
外に持ち出したのかもしれない｡
Maybe Sakurajima-senpai herself acted
as the valve that leaked the "flow" outside.
違ったとしても 空気なんて
簡単に伝染する｡
Even if she didn't, it's everywhere around us all.
みんな勝手に空気を読む時代だし｡
And modern society's more than happy
to go with the flow.
《目に見えない空気｡
The flow. Invisible, but nobody can deny its existence.
確かに そこに存在している空気｡
戦うなんてﾊﾞｶﾊﾞｶしい空気…》
Something that'd be entirely pointless to fight.
(理央)寝ている間は 相手を
意識することができないからね｡
One can't be cognizant of
another person in their sleep.
意識が途切れたﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞで
So the moment they fall asleep,
she becomes invisible to them.
空気化の現象に
飲み込まれてしまうんだろう｡
眠ったら忘れる…｡
I'll forget about her if I sleep.
What are you drinking, Onii-chan?
(かえで)お兄ちゃん
何飲んでるんですか？
明日から３日間
中間ﾃｽﾄだからな｡
An energy drink. I've got midterms for the next three days.
かえでは もう寝ろ｡
You go to bed, Kaede.
I need to do this while I've still got my focus.
意識がはっきりしているうちに
やっておかないと…｡
《この先に記されていることは
Frankly, I know the following story
will be hard to believe.
正直 信じられないようなことだと
思うけど
全部 本当のことなので
必ず最後まで読むように｡
But it's all true, so make sure you read all the way to the end.
必ずだ》
You have to.
しまりのない顔ね｡
You look completely out of it.
麻衣さんは 今日も美人ですね｡
And you look as beautiful as always.
ﾈｸﾀｲ曲がってる｡
Your tie's all crooked.
まさか こんなに早く 麻衣さんと
新婚ﾌﾟﾚｲができるとは
I never thought I'd get to play newlyweds with you so soon.
思いませんでした｡
ﾊﾞｶは顔だけにしなさい｡
Contain the stupidity to your face.
麻衣さんも 試験受けるんですか？
ｶﾝﾆﾝｸﾞし放題じゃないですか｡
You're taking the exams too?
You can cheat all you want.
そんなことしなくても私
勉強できるから｡
I don't have to cheat. I've done my homework.
でも 答案用紙
配ってもらえないんじゃ
That doesn't mean anything if they won't hand me the exam paper, though.
意味ないけどね｡
But you're still going to school? How diligent.
それでも学校に行くなんて
麻衣さんは まじめだな｡
家にいても 他にすることないし｡
Well, it's not like I'd have anything to do at home.
それに 今日になったら
咲太以外の誰かに
Besides, some other people might be able to see me today.
見えるように
なってるかもしれないしね｡
May 27th - Day 1 of Midterms
《ﾀﾞﾒだ 眠るな…｡
No. Don't fall asleep.
If you do, you'll forget about her.
眠ったら忘れる｡
Don't fall asleep!
眠るな！》
梓川 その目の下のｸﾏは
一夜漬けか？
Azusagawa, what's with the bags under your eyes? Pulled an all-nighter?
双葉…｡
ん？
Futaba...
お前 覚えてるか？
は？ 何のこと？
Do you remember?
Huh? Remember what?
いや いいんだ じゃあな｡
Never mind. It's nothing.
Later.
Your hypothesis was right on the money, huh?
お前の仮説は正しかったわけか｡
すげえ燃える展開だな｡
If this doesn't get me fired up, nothing will!
Is there no other way?
《何か方法はないのか
何か 何か…》
Quantum Physics for Dummies
There's gotta be something!
お前 ｿﾞﾝﾋﾞみたいになってんぞ｡
Dude, you look like a zombie.
May 28th - Day 2 of Midterms
何を買ったの？
What did you buy?
Oh, uh...
あっ え～…｡
やっぱり寝てないんだ｡
You really haven't been sleeping, huh?
ほら 座りなさい
明日が試験最終日でしょ｡
Come on. Sit down.
Tomorrow's the last day of midterms, right?
勉強 見てあげるから｡
I'll tutor you.
ﾊﾞﾆｰｶﾞｰﾙの格好で
教えてくれるんなら 頑張ります｡
If you teach me in your
bunny-girl outfit, I'll do my best.
そんなことしたら 咲太の脳内は
ｴｯﾁなことばっかりになって
If I did that, your head would be too filled with dirty thoughts to study.
勉強にならないでしょ｡
それは盲点だった｡
Right. I hadn't thought of that.
ﾃｽﾄで100点がとれたら
ご褒美をあげるから｡
Work hard and get a perfect score,
and I'll give you a reward.
Is this one of those "I'll do anything you want" deals?
それって
何でもしてくれるってやつ？
何でもっていっても
Yes, but there are limits.
本当に 何でも
してあげるわけじゃないからね｡
じゃあ ｢一緒にお風呂入る｣
で我慢する｡
I'll settle for just taking a bath together, then.
ｱｳﾄよ それ｡
なら この間できなかった
That's not happening either.
Then how about we go on that
Kamakura date we missed out on last time?
鎌倉ﾃﾞｰﾄをするっていうのは？
いいけど…｡
Sure, but are you really okay with that?
本当に それでいいの？
You want something more extreme, huh?
麻衣さんは もっと
過激なやつをご所望かぁ｡
そんなこと言ってない｡
あ～ 目が覚めるなぁ｡
I did not say anything of the sort.
Man, that really wakes me up.
ﾎﾝﾄ 年下のくせに
生意気なんだから｡
For a younger boy, you really are cheeky.
まずは現国 漢字の問題から｡
Let's start with Modern Japanese.
Nouns and verbs.
咲太の未来をﾎｼｮｳしてくれる人は
誰もいないの ｢ﾎｼｮｳ｣と
Classify the instances of "guarantee" from
"Nobody is willing to guarantee Sakuta's future"
咲太の老後には何のﾎｼｮｳもないの
｢ﾎｼｮｳ｣を
and "There's no guarantee
Sakuta will lead a happy retired life"
それぞれ漢字にしなさい｡
先生 問題文に悪意を感じます｡
into "noun" or "verb."
Sensei, I sense malice emanating from the question.
いいから書いて｡
Just answer it.
咲太の未来をﾎｼｮｳしてくれる人は
誰もいないの ｢ﾎｼｮｳ｣は どっち？
Which one is the "guarantee" from
"Nobody is willing to guarantee Sakuta's future"?
Uh...
え～っと…
すみません ﾋﾝﾄをください｡
Sorry. Please give me a hint.
こっちは請け負うって意味で
One means "to take responsibility for,"
and the other means "assurance."
こっちは守るっていうような意味｡
ということは
麻衣さんの幸せな未来は
So the one in "I'll guarantee
Mai-san's happy future" is a verb,
僕がﾎｼｮｳしますが こっちで
and the one in "We have a guarantee
for a wonderful married life" is a noun?
２人の将来には 充実した
ﾎｼｮｳがあるは こっちってこと…｡
勝手に問題文を変えないの｡
Don't go changing the question.
妹さんは？
もう寝たみたいです｡
What's your sister up to?
Gone to bed already, I think.
麻衣さんは 一人っ子？
妹がいる｡
Are you an only child?
I have a younger sister.
あの母親と別れた父親が
再婚してから生まれた子だけど｡
A half-sister, though. My parents divorced,
and my dad had her with his new wife.
かわいいですか？
私ほどじゃない｡
Is she cute?
Not as cute as me.
うわぁ 大人げねえ｡
Wow, talk about petty.
自分のほうがかわいいって
自覚あるくせに
Do you like girls who praise other girls' looks
despite knowing they're the more attractive one?
別の誰かのことを
かわいい～とか言ってる女が
咲太は好きなの？
それ 嫌いなﾀｲﾌﾟ｡
Nah, I hate those types.
でしょ？
Right?
だからって 妹さんまで…｡
But come on. She's your sister.
よかった
ちゃんと効いたみたいね｡
Good.
I'm glad they worked.
僕は まだ眠るわけには…｡
I can't go to sleep yet.
咲太は よく頑張ったわ｡
You did great, Sakuta.
私のために頑張ってくれた｡
You tried so hard for me.
違う まだまだ こんなんじゃ…｡
No... I'm not done yet.
だから もう十分 もういいから｡
You've done more than enough. You can rest now.
よくない…｡
No... I can't.
もともと私は
ひとりだったんだから 大丈夫よ｡
I've always been alone anyway.
I'll be fine.
咲太に忘れられるくらい
何でもない｡
It won't bother me one bit if you forget about me.
それでも 今日までありがとう｡
But still, thanks for everything.
それと ごめんね｡
And I'm sorry.
おやすみ 咲太｡
Good night, Sakuta.
さよなら｡
And goodbye.
Teenage Pig Doesn't
Dream of Bunny Girls
...chan! Onii-chan! Wake up!
(かえで)お兄ちゃん 朝です｡
Isn't today the last day of midterms?
今日まで試験ですよね？
遅刻しますよ？
Do you want to be late?
You're a lifesaver, Kaede.
ああ 助かったよ かえで
起こしてくれて ありがとう｡
Thanks for waking me up.
こ これは何ですか？
Wh-What is this?
I bought it for you to wear, I guess?
かえでに着せようと
思ったのかな？
N-No way!
き 着ません！
こういうｾｸｼｰ路線の服は
I'm not ready to wear such sexy outfits yet!
かえでには まだ早いです！
May 29th
"Frankly, I know the following story will be hard to believe.
｢この先に記されていることは
正直 信じられないようなことだと
思うけど
But it's all true, so make sure you read all the way to the end.
全部 本当のことなので
必ず最後まで読むように｡
You have to."
必ずだ｣｡
なんだ これ？
What is this?
"May 6th.
｢５月６日
野生のﾊﾞﾆｰｶﾞｰﾙに出会った｡
I ran into a bunny girl in the wild.
その正体は 峰ヶ原高校の
３年の先輩
It was a student at Minegahara High,
one year my senior.
The celebrity..."
あの有名人… だ｣｡
僕の黒歴史というやつか｡
What is this, an old creative writing exercise?
《確かに 大垣には行ったけど
Yeah, I did go to Ogaki,
but wasn't that just a solo trip?
あれは ただの一人旅だったよな》
We were both tired, so
Mai-san used the shower...
...sound of the shower alone...
...called on the phone...
We were both silent for a while.
"Hey, want to kiss?"
Mai-san asked suddenly.
I thought for a moment.
-
san
彼女ができたら
埋めろってことか？
Am I supposed to fill in the blanks
once I get a girlfriend?
You look a lot better today.
今日は だいぶ顔色がいいな｡
あ？
You were like a zombie the last couple days.
昨日までは
ｿﾞﾝﾋﾞみたいな顔してたろ｡
咲太って 試験前に一夜漬けとか
するﾀｲﾌﾟだったっけ？
Were you always the type to pull all-nighters before exams?
いや 諦めて さっさと寝るﾀｲﾌﾟ｡
だよな｡
Nah. I'm the type to throw in the towel and go to sleep.
Figures.
What's up?
どした？
いや 視線を感じたっていうか…｡
Well...
It felt like someone was staring at me.
Hey.
おう｡
これ｡
Here.
A love letter?
ﾗﾌﾞなﾚﾀｰ？
違うよ｡
Hell no.
｢あらゆる物質は
誰かに観測されることで
"Assumption: all things and states are only determined to exist when they're observed."
この世に物質としての形が
確定すると仮定する｣｡
なんだ こりゃ？
私にも わかんない｡
The heck is this?
I have no idea either.
教科書に挟まってて
今朝 気づいた｡
I found it in my textbook this morning.
これと一緒に｡
Along with this note.
Give this letter
to Azusagawa
じゃ 確かに渡したからね｡
Well, my job here is done.
｢…の消滅が 全校生徒の
無自覚な無視に
"If blank's disappearance is caused by the student body's subconscious ignoring of her,
起因するのであれば
それを上回る存在理由を
then Azusagawa just needs to give her a different purpose in their heads.
梓川が作り出せばいい｡
In other words, his love just needs to overwrite their cognizance, or lack thereof."
つまり 全校生徒の無意識を
梓川の愛が
上回ればいいという話だ｣｡
愛ねぇ…｡
Love, huh?
High
School
Second
Year
Modern
Japanese
Exam
High
School
Second
Year
Modern
Japanese
Exam
2. Classify the following
words as either noun or verb.
Guarantee (noun)
Guarantee (verb)
One means "to take responsibility for,"
and the other means "assurance."
⦅こっちは請け負うって意味で
こっちは守るっていうような意味｡
咲太の未来をﾎｼｮｳしてくれる人は
誰もいないの ｢ﾎｼｮｳ｣と
Classify the instances of "guarantee" from
"Nobody is willing to guarantee Sakuta's future"
咲太の老後には何のﾎｼｮｳもないの
｢ﾎｼｮｳ｣を
and "There's no guarantee
Sakuta will lead a happy retired life"
それぞれ漢字にしなさい⦆
into "noun" or "verb."
あれ？
Huh?
梓川 どうした？
What's the matter, Azusagawa?
Number two!
大のほうです！
《大事なことを思い出した｡
I've remembered something important:
大切な人の記憶がよみがえった｡
the memories of someone dear to me.
これから僕が相手をするのは
空気だ｡
What I'm going to be fighting now is the flow.
押しても引いても叩いても
何もない あの空気｡
The flow you can't pull, push, or hit.
学校を取り巻く空気｡
The flow coursing all through this school.
Living life going with the flow is easy.
右にならえの行き方は楽でいい｡
悪いことの判断を
全部自分でするのは
Thinking for yourself about what's right and wrong takes energy,
ｶﾛﾘｰを使うし
and you can get hurt if you have views of your own that are rejected.
自分の意思を持つと
否定されたときに
傷つくことになる｡
On the other hand, following the herd gives you safety and security.
その点 みんなと一緒であれば
安心安全でいられる｡
見たくないものを見ずにいられる｡
You can be blind to things you don't want to see,
考えたくないことを
考えずにいられる｡
ignorant to things you don't want to think about.
全部 ひと事で済ませられる｡
You can sweep it all under the rug.
だけど… みんながそうしてるから
ってだけで
But everyone else doing it
doesn't justify hurting someone.
誰かを苦しめていいなんて
理屈はない｡
Everyone else saying or doing something doesn't make it right.
みんながそうしてるから
みんながそう言ってるから
それが正しいとも限らない｡
だいたい ｢みんな｣って 誰だ？
Who is "everyone," anyway?
Kanagawa Prefectural Minegahara High School
いつも僕を年下扱いで
からかってきた彼女｡
She always plays the
older-girl card to mess with me.
お色気ﾈﾀで自爆して
顔を真っ赤にしていた彼女｡
She always digs her own grave with dirty talk
and leaves herself red-faced.
その失敗を隠そうとして
意地になって強がってた彼女｡
And then, she gets all stubborn
and tries to hide her embarrassment.
わがままで 女王様で 気分屋で
She's selfish, bossy, capricious,
そのくせ意外とうぶだった
一つ年上の先輩｡
and surprisingly naïve for a girl
who's a year older than me.
もう無視なんかさせない｡
I won't let you guys ignore her anymore. I won't let you turn a blind eye.
見て見ぬふりなんかさせない｡
できないくらいに みんなの記憶に
刻みつけてやる！》
I'm going to etch her into your memories so vividly that you won't be able to!
もう空気なんて読んでやるか｡
I'm done going with the flow. Screw that!
ﾊﾞｶﾊﾞｶしい！
いいか お前ら よく聞け！
Listen up well, you jerks!
I'm Azusagawa Sakuta, roll number 1 in class 2-1,
２年１組の出席番号１番
梓川咲太は
３年１組の
桜島麻衣先輩のことが…｡
and Sakurajima Mai of class 3-1...
ﾊｧ… 桜島先輩のことが
is the one I love!
好きだ～!!
I love Sakurajima-senpai!
あ～ ｸｿ やっぱり こうなるのか｡
Shit! I should've known this would happen!
恥のかき損だよ ったく｡
I embarrassed myself for nothing!
これだから空気となんか
戦いたくなかったんだ｡
This is why I didn't want to fight the flow!
ﾁｸｼｮｰ！ 麻衣さん 好きだ！
Damn it all!
Mai-san, I love you!
好きだ 好きだ 好きだ
好きだ 好きだ～!!
I love, love, love, love, love you!
麻衣さん 好きだ！
Mai-san, I love you!
I want to hold hands and walk down Shichirigahama Beach with you!
手をつないで
七里ヶ浜を歩きたい！
ﾊﾞﾆｰｶﾞｰﾙの格好だって
もう一度見たい！
I want to see you as a bunny girl again!
ぎゅっと抱きしめてみたいし
I want to hold you tight,
ｷｽだってしたいんだ！
and I want to kiss you too!
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
要するにさぁ 麻衣さん
Long story short, Mai-san!
大 大 大 大 大好きだ～!!
I super-duper-ultra-giga love you!
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
You don't have to yell like a madman. I can hear you.
そんなに大きな声で
言われなくても 聞こえてる｡
近所迷惑でしょ｡
You're being a nuisance, you know.
I figured I might as well let everyone around the world know.
どうせだから 世界中の人に
知ってもらおうと思って｡
ﾊﾞｶなんだから｡
You're such an idiot.
賢いふりしてるやつよりは
いいでしょ｡
Better to be an idiot than someone pretending to be smart, right?
ﾎﾝﾄ ﾊﾞｶ｡
A complete and utter fool!
Doing this will only make people
spread weird rumors about you again!
こんなことして目立ったら
またﾍﾝなうわさが立つわよ｡
麻衣さんとうわさされるなら
大歓迎｡
I'd be perfectly fine with a few rumors about you and me.
そうじゃなくて…｡
That's not the point.
ﾊﾞｶ… ﾊﾞｶ咲太｡
You idiot.
Sakuta, you idiot.
ｲｯ… えっ なんで？
What? Why?
You liar! You said you wouldn't forget!
ｳｿつき 忘れないって
言ったじゃない！
You said you'd never forget!
絶対に忘れないって｡
ごめん…｡
Sorry.
許さない｡
ごめん…｡
I won't forgive you.
I'm sorry.
絶対に許さない｡
I'll never forgive you.
じゃあ 許してくれるまで
離さない｡
I won't let you go until you do.
だったら 一生許さない｡
Then I won't for the rest of my life.
え～｡
なによ 嫌なの？
Huh?
What, do you have a problem with that?
私に ここまで言わせておいて…｡
After all you're making me say?
あの… 足｡
Uh...
Your foot...
踏まれて うれしいんでしょ？
ごめん ごめんなさい｡
Aren't you happy I'm stepping on you?
Sorry. I'm sorry.
It won't happen again, so please forgive me.
反省しているので
許してください｡
他に言うことは？
踏んでもらえて幸せです｡
Anything else?
I feel very fortunate to have you step on me.
今 私が聞きたいのは
そんな言葉じゃない｡
That's not what I want to hear right now.
好きです…｡
I like you.
ﾎﾝﾄに？
Really?
Not really.
ｳｿです 大好きです｡
I love you.
ねぇ 咲太｡
なに？
Hey, Sakuta.
What?
今の １か月後に
もう一度言って｡
Say that again one month from now.
なんで？
ここで返事すると
Why?
If I gave you an answer now, I'd feel like I got carried away in the heat of the moment.
勢いと雰囲気で
押し切られた感じがする｡
僕としては この場で
ｷｽくらいまでしたいんだけど｡
Personally, I'd like to kiss you right here and now.
今ﾄﾞｷﾄﾞｷしてるのも
Maybe my heart is only beating so fast right now
in the heat of the moment, too.
こういう状況だからかも
しれないし｡
麻衣さん 意外と冷静だね｡
You're awfully calm and collected about this.
じゃあ １か月待てないから
毎日言ってもいい？
Well, I can't wait a month, so can I say it every day?
いいけど｡ ちゃんと
１か月続けなさいよ｡
Sure, but you'd better keep it up
for the whole month.
できなかったら
気が変わったんだと見なすから｡
If you don't, I'll assume that you changed your mind.
みんな ﾎﾝﾄ
空気を読むのが好きよね｡
People sure do love going with the flow.
咲太が同級生を
病院送りにしたっていううわさ
You know that rumor about Sakuta
sending his classmates to the hospital?
あれ ﾃﾞﾀﾗﾒだから！
It's complete hogwash!
なんで桜島先輩
そんなの知ってんだ？
Why does Sakurajima-senpai know about that?
てか ２人は どういう関係？
What's their deal, anyway?
みんなに
言ってほしかったんでしょ？
There. I told them like you wanted.
麻衣さんのせいで
すげえ注目されてる｡
Thanks to you, I'm the center of attention now.
職員室でお説教とか 憂鬱だな｡
Am I going to get lectured in the staff room? Boy, will that suck.
いいじゃない｡
Hey, no big deal.
私も一緒に怒られてあげるから｡
I'll be there to get yelled at with you.
まっ それなら悪くないか｡
I guess that doesn't sound too bad.
そこの２人 ちょっと来い！
You two over there!
Come with me!
《こうして世界は
桜島麻衣を取り戻した》
And so, Sakurajima Mai once again became a part of our world.
June 2nd
やっぱ 咲太の心臓って
鉄でできてんだな｡
Your heart's gotta be made of steel, Sakuta.
私だったら恥ずかしくて死んでる｡
I would've died of embarrassment by now.
さすが梓川 青春ﾌﾞﾀ野郎だね｡
But that's our Azusagawa.
The most teenage of teenage pigs.
それ どういう意味だよ｡
What's that supposed to mean?
When rumors of the hospitalization incident spread all around school,
病院送りのうわさが
学校中に流れたとき
空気と戦うなんて
ﾊﾞｶﾊﾞｶしいとか言ってたの
you said it'd be entirely pointless to fight the flow, remember?
忘れた？
言ってたな｡
He totally did.
自分のためには
本気になれなかったくせに
You couldn't lift a finger for your own sake,
美人の先輩のためになら
どんな恥もかけるなんてやつが
but you were willing to make a spectacle out of yourself for a hot older girl.
青春ﾌﾞﾀ野郎じゃなくて 何なのよ｡
What does that make you
if not a total teenage pig?
なぁ 結局 双葉の仮説が
正しかったってことでいいのか？
So in the end, was your hypothesis proven right?
さあね 思春期の不安定な精神や
Who knows?
If the illusions caused by teenage instability and warped worldview
強烈な思い込みが見せるまやかし｡
そういうのが思春期症候群だって
いうなら
are what you call Puberty Syndrome,
科学的な検証なんて
あてにならないよ｡
then the scientific method
isn't going to help with that.
まぁ でも 私たちの世界なんて
But, hey, maybe our world is so simple
that a mere confession can turn it on its head.
告白ひとつで
ｶﾞﾗｯと変わってしまうくらいに
単純なのかもね｡
梓川が証明したようにさ｡
As you proved.
そうかもな｡
Yeah, maybe.
But that wasn't to be the last incident related to Puberty Syndrome.
After Schrödinger's cat
came Laplace's demon, or well,
《だけど 思春期症候群に
まつわる事件は
これで終わりじゃなかった｡
Laplace's little devil.
ｼｭﾚﾃﾞｨﾝｶﾞｰの猫の次は
ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽの悪魔
That's my Senpai. A total pig.
いや ﾗﾌﾟﾗｽのﾌﾟﾁﾃﾞﾋﾞﾙが現れたんだ》
Next Episode
#4: No Tomorrow for Pigs